Wonder by R.J. Palacio.
the Drop-Off.
THE GRADUATION CEREMONY was held in the Beecher Prep Upper School auditorium.. It
was only about a 15-minute walk from our house to the other campus building,, but
Dad drove me because I was all dressed up and had on new shiny black shoes that
weren’t broken in yet, and I didn’t want my feet to hurt..
Students were supposed to arrive at the auditorium an hour before the ceremony
started,, but we got there even earlier,.
so, we sat in the car and waited.. Dad turned on the CD player, and our favorite
song came on..
We both smiled and started bobbing our heads to the music..
Dad sang along with the song, "And he would bicycle across town in the rain to
bring you candy."
"“Hey,, is my tie on straight?”?" I said..
He looked and straightened it a tiny bit as he kept on singing:. "And John bought
a gown for you to wear to the prom."
"“Does my hair look okay?”?" I said..
He smiled and nodded.. "“Perfect,”," he said.. "“You look great,, Auggie.”."
"“Via put some gel in it this morning,”," I said,, pulling down the sun visor and
looking in the little mirror..
"“It doesn’t look too puffy?”?" "“No,, it’s very,, very cool,, Auggie..
I don’t think you’ve ever had it this short before,, have you?”?"
"“No,. I got a cut yesterday.. I think it makes me look more grown-up,, don’t you?”?"
"“Definitely!”."
He was smiling,, looking at me and nodding..
"“But I’m the luckiest guy on the Lower East Side, cuz I got wheels, and you want
to go for a ride."
"“Look at you,, Auggie!”," he said,, smiling from ear to ear..
"“Look at you,, looking so grown up and spiffy..
I can’t believe you’re graduating from the fifth grade!”.
“I know,, it’s pretty awesome,, right?”? I nodded..
“It feels just like yesterday that you started.”.
“Remember, I still had that Star Wars braid hanging from the back of my head?”.
“Oh my gosh,, that’s right,”, he said,, rubbing his palm over his forehead..
“You hated that braid,, didn’t you,, Dad?”?
“Hate is too strong a word,, but I definitely didn’t love it.”.
“You hated it,. come on,, admit it,”, I teased.. “No,, I didn’t hate it.”, He smiled,,
shaking his head..
“But I will admit to hating that astronaut helmet you used to wear,. do you remember?”?
“The one Miranda gave me?? Of course I remember!. I used to wear that thing all the time.”.
“Good God,, I hated that thing,”, he laughed,, almost more to himself..
“I was so bummed when it got lost,”, I said..
“Oh,, it didn’t get lost,”, he answered casually.. “I threw it out.”.
“Wait., What?”? I said.. I honestly didn’t think I heard him right..
The day is beautiful, and so are you, he was singing..
“Dad!”, I said,, turning down the volume.
What?”? he said.. “You threw it out?!”?
He finally looked at my face and saw how mad I was..
I couldn’t believe he was being so matter-of-fact about the whole thing..
I mean,, to me, this was a major revelation, and he was acting like it was
no big deal..
“Auggie,, I couldn’t stand seeing that thing cover your face anymore,”, he said clumsily..
“Dad,, I loved that helmet!. It meant a lot to me!.
I was bummed beyond belief when it got lost—. —don’t you remember?”?
“Of course I remember, Augie, he said softly.
Oh, Augie, don’t be mad.. I’m sorry.. I just couldn’t stand seeing you wear that
thing on your head anymore,, you know?? I didn’t think it was good for you.”.
He was trying to look me in the eye,, but I wouldn’t look at him..
“Come on, Augie. please try to understand,”, he continued,, putting his
hand under my chin and tilting my face toward him..
“You were wearing that helmet all the time., And the real, real, real truth is:
I miss seeing your face, Augie.
I know you don’t always love it,, but you have to understand.
I love it.. I love this face of yours, Augie, completely and passionately.. And
it kind of broke my heart that you were always covering it up.”.
He was squinting at me like he really wanted me to understand..
“Does Mom know?”? I said.. He opened his eyes wide.. “No way.. Are you kidding?? She
would have killed me!”.
“She tore the place apart looking for that helmet,, Dad,”, I said.. “I mean,, she
spent like a week looking for it in every closet,, in the laundry room,,
everywhere.”. “I know!”, he said,, nodding..
“That’s why she’d kill me!”.
And then he looked at me,, and something about his expression made me start laughing,,
which made him open his mouth wide like he’d just realized something..
“Wait a minute, Augie, he said,, pointing his finger at me..
“You have to promise me you will never tell Mommy about this.”.
I smiled and rubbed my palms together like I was about to get very greedy..
"“Let’s see,”." I said,, stroking my chin..
"“I’ll be wanting that new Xbox when it comes out next month.. And I’ll
definitely be wanting my own car in about 6 years,.
a red Porsche would be nice,. and" He started laughing..
I love it when I’m the one who makes Dad
laugh, since he’s usually the funny man that gets everybody else laughing..
"“Oh boy,, oh boy,”." he said,, shaking his head..
"“You really have grown up.”."
The part of the song we love to sing the
most started to play, and I turned up the volume.. We both started singing..
"I’m the ugliest guy on the lorry Side,,
but I’ve got wheels and you want to go for a ride..
Want to go for a ride..
Want to go for a ride."
We always sang this last part at the top of our lungs, trying to hold that last
note as long as the guy who sang the song, which always made us crack up..
While we were laughing,, we noticed Jack had arrived and was walking over to our car..
I started to get out..
"“Hold on,”." said Dad..
"“I just want to make sure you’ve forgiven me,.
okay?”?"
"“Yes, I'll forgive you.”."
He looked at me gratefully..
"“Thank you.”.
“But don’t ever throw anything else of mine out again without telling me!”."
"“I promise.”."
I opened the door and got out just as Jack reached the car..
"“Hey, Jack,”." I said..
"“Hey, Auggie..
Hey, Mr.. Pullman,”." said Jack.. "“How you doing Jack?”?" said Dad..
"“See you later,, Dad,”." I said,, closing the door.. "“Good luck,, guys!”." Dad called
out, rolling down the front window..
“See you on the other side of fifth grade.
Take your seats everyone.
JACK AND I walked right behind a couple of sixth graders into the building, and
then followed them to the auditorium..
Mrs.. G was at the entrance, handing out the programs and telling kids where to go..
“Fifth graders down the aisle to the left,”, she said..
“Sixth graders go to the right.. Everyone come in., Come in.. Good morning..
Go to your staging areas..
Fifth graders to the left,, sixth grade to the right.
The auditorium was huge inside..
Big sparkly chandeliers., Red velvet walls., Rows and rows and rows of
cushioned seats leading up to the giant stage..
We walked down the wide aisle and followed the signs to the fifth grade
staging area,, which was in a big room to the left of the stage..
Inside were four rows of folding chairs facing the front of the room,, which is
where Miss Reuben was standing, waving us in as soon as we walked in the room..
“Okay,, kids,, take your seats., Take your seats,”, she was saying, pointing to the
rows of chairs..
“Don’t forget, you’re sitting alphabetically.. Come on, everybody,, take your seats.”.
Not too many kids had arrived yet, though, and the ones who had weren’t listening to her..
Me and Jack were sword fighting with our rolled up programs..
“Hey, guys.”.
It was Summer walking over to us.. She was wearing a light pink dress and, I
think, a little makeup.
Well, Summer,, you look awesome,”, I told her, because she really did..
“Really?? Thanks,. you too,, Auggie.”.
“Yeah,, you look okay,, Summer,”, said Jack, kind of matter-of-factly..
And for the first time,, I realized that Jack had a crush on her..
"“This is so exciting,, isn’t it?”?" said Summer..
"“Yeah,, kind of,”." I answered,, nodding..
"“Oh, man,, look at this program,”." said Jack,, scratching his forehead.. "“We’re
going to be here all freaking day.”."
I looked at my program..
Headmaster’s Opening Remarks, Dr.. Harold Jansen.
Middle school Director’s Address, Mr..
Lawrence Tushman. Light and Day Middle School Choir. Fifth grade Student
Commencement Address, Zamina Chen.
Pachelbel: “Canon in D, Middle School Chamber Music Ensemble.
Sixth grade Student Commencement Address, Mark Antoine Aucoin. Under
Pressure, Middle School Choir. Middle School Dean’s Address, Ms.. Jennifer
Reuben. Awards Presentation, (see back).
Roll Call of Names.
"What do you think that?”?" I asked..
"“Because Mr.. Jansen’s speech is going forever,”." said Jack.. "“He’s even worse
than Tushman!”."
"“My mom said she actually dozed off when he spoke last year,”." Summer added..
"“What’s the awards presentation?”?" I asked..
"“That’s where they give medals to the biggest brainiacs,”." Jack answered..
"“Which would mean Charlotte and Zamina will win everything in the fifth grade,,
like they won everything in the fourth grade, and in the third grade.”."
"“Not in the second grade?”?" I laughed..
"“They didn’t give those awards out in the second grade,”." he answered..
"“Maybe you’ll win this year,”." I joked..
"“Not unless they give awards for the most C's." he laughed..
"“Everybody,, take your seats!”." Ms. Reuben started yelling louder now,, like she was
getting annoyed that nobody was listening. "We've got a lot to get
through,, so take your seats..
Don’t forget, you’re sitting in alphabetical order!. A through G is the
first row!. H through N is the second row;. O through Q is the third row;. R
through Z is the last row.. Let’s go,, people.”.
"“We should go sit down,”." said Summer, walking toward the front section..
"“You guys are definitely coming over to my house after this,, right?”?" I called
out after her..
"“Definitely!”." she said, taking her seat next to Zamina Chin..
"“When did Summer get so hot?”?" Jack muttered in my ear..
"“Shut up,, dude,”." I said, laughing as we headed toward the third row..
"“Seriously,. when did that happen?”?" he whispered, taking the seat next to mine..
"“Mr.. Will!”." Ms. Reuben shouted.. "“Last time I checked,, W came between R and Z.
yes?”?"
Jack looked at her blankly..
"“Dude,, you’re in the wrong row!”." I said..
"“I am?”?"
And the face he made as he got up to leave,, which was a mixture of looking
completely confused and looking like he’s just playing a joke on someone,,
totally cracked me up.
A Simple Thing ABOUT AN HOUR later, we were all seated in the giant auditorium waiting for Mr..
Tushman to give his middle school address.”.
The auditorium was even bigger than I imagined it would be—.
—bigger even than the one at Via school..
I looked around, and there must have been a million people in the audience..
Okay,, maybe not a million,, but definitely a lot..
"“Thank you,, Headmaster Jansen,, for those very kind words of introduction,”." said
Mr.. Tushman, standing behind the podium on the stage as he talked into the microphone..
"“Welcome,, my fellow teachers and members of the faculty..
“Welcome, parents and grandparents,, friends and honored guests,, and most
especially,, welcome to my fifth- and sixth grade students..
“Welcome to the Beecher Prep Middle School graduation ceremonies!!!”.
Everyone applauded..
"“Every year,”," continued Mr.. Tushman,, reading from his notes with his reading
glasses way down on the tip of his nose,, "“I am charged with writing two
commencement addresses:. one for the fifth- and sixth grade graduation
ceremony today,, and one for the seventh- and eighth grade ceremony that will take
place tomorrow..
And every year I say to myself,, 'Let me cut down on my work and write
just one address that I can use for both situations..
Seems like it shouldn’t be such a hard thing to do,, right??'
And yet, each year I still end up with two different speeches,, no matter what
my intentions,. and I finally figured out why this year..
It’s not,, as you might assume,, simply because tomorrow I’ll be talking to an
older crowd with a middle school experience that is largely behind them—,
—whereas your middle school experience is largely in front of you..
No,, I think it has to do more with this particular age that you are right now,.
this particular moment in your lives that,, even after 20 years of my being
around students this age,, still moves me..
Because you’re at the cusp,, kids.. You’re at the edge between childhood and
everything that comes after.. You’re in transition.. “We are all gathered here
together,”," Mr.. Tushman continued,, taking off his glasses and using them to point
at all of us in the audience,.
"“all your families,, friends,, and teachers, to celebrate not only your
achievements of this past year,, Beecher middle schoolers—, —but your endless possibilities..
“When you reflect on this past year,, I want you all to look at where you are
now and where you’ve been..
You’ve all gotten a little taller,, a little stronger,, a little smarter, I hope.”.
Here some people in the audience chuckled..
“But the best way to measure how you’ve grown isn’t by inches or the number of
laps you can now run around the track, or even your grade point average.
Those those things are important, to be sure..
It’s what you’ve done with your time,, how you’ve chosen to spend your days,,
and whom you have touched this year..
That, to me, is the greatest measure of success..
“There’s a wonderful line in a book by J..
M.. Barrie—. —and no,, it’s not Peter Pan,
and I’m not going to ask you to clap if you believe in fairies..
Here everyone laughed again..
“But in another book by J.. M.. Barrie called The Little White Bird, he writes,
He started flipping through a small book on the podium until he found the page he
was looking for,. and then he put on his reading glasses..
“‘Shall we make a new rule of life?
always to try to be a little kinder than is necessary?’”.
Here Mr.. Tushman looked up at the audience..
“Kinder than is necessary,”, he repeated..
“What a marvelous line,, isn’t it??
Kinder than is necessary.
Because it’s not enough to be kind..
One should be kinder than needed..
Why I love that line,, that concept,, is that it reminds me that we carry with
us, as human beings, not just the capacity to be kind,, but the very choice of kindness..
And what does that mean??
How is that measured??
You can’t use a yardstick..
It’s like I was saying just before:.
it’s not like measuring how much you’ve grown in a year..
It’s not exactly quantifiable,, is it??
How do we know we’ve been kind?? What is being kind, anyway?”?
He put on his reading glasses again and started flipping through another small book..
“There’s another passage in a different book I’d like to share with you,”, he said.,
“If you’ll bear with me until I find it..
Ah,, here we go. And Under the Eye of the Clock by Christopher Nolan,, the main
character is a young man who is facing some extraordinary challenges..
There’s this one part where someone helps him:.
a kid in his class.. On the surface,, it’s a small gesture., But to this young man,,
whose name is Joseph,, it’s well,, if you’ll permit me.
He cleared his throat and read from the book:.
“‘It was at moments such as these that Joseph recognized the face of God in
human form.. It glimmered in their kindness to him,. it glowed in their
keenness,. it hinted in their caring,.
indeed, it caressed in their gaze.’”.
He paused and took off his reading glasses again..
“It glimmered in their kindness to him,”, he repeated,, smiling..
“Such a simple thing,, kindness.. Such a simple thing.. A nice word of
encouragement given when needed., An act of friendship., A passing smile.”.
He closed the book,, put it down,, and leaned forward on the podium..
“Children,, what I want to impart to you today is an understanding of the value of that
simple thing called kindness.. And that’s all I want to leave you with today..
I know I’m kind of infamous for my, um, verbosity.
Here, everybody laughed again..
I guess he knew he was known for his long speeches..
but what I want you,, my students,, to take away from your middle school
experience,”," he continued,, "“is the sure knowledge that, in the
future, you make for yourselves,, anything is possible.. If every single
person in this room made it a rule that wherever you are,, whenever you can,,
you will try to act a little kinder than is necessary—, —the world really would be a better
place..
And if you do this,, if you act just a little kinder than is
necessary,, someone else,, somewhere,, someday, may recognize in you,, in every single
one of you,, the face of God.”."
He paused and shrugged..
"“Or whatever politically correct spiritual representative of universal
goodness you happen to believe in,”," he added quickly,, smiling,.
which got a lot of laughs and loads of applause,, especially from the back of
the auditorium,, where the parents were sitting.
Awards. I LIKED MR.. TUSHMAN’S speech,, but I have to admit:, I kind of zoned out
a little during some of the other speeches..
I tuned in again as Miss Reuben started reading off the names of the kids who’d
made the High Honor Roll because we were supposed to stand up when our names were
called.. So, I waited and listened for my name as she went down the list
alphabetically. Reed Kingsley., Maya Markowitz., August Pullman.. I stood up..
Then when she finished reading off the names,, she asked all of us to face the
audience and take a bow,, and everyone applauded..
I had no idea where in that huge crowd my parents might be sitting.. All I could
see were the flashes of light from people taking photos and parents waving
at their kids.. I pictured Mom waving at me from somewhere, even though I I see her..
Then Mr.. Tushman came back to the podium to present the medals for academic
excellence,, and Jack was right. Zemina Chen won the gold medal for “overall
academic excellence in the fifth grade.”.
Charlotte won the silver..
Charlotte also won a gold medal for music..
Amos won the medal for overall excellence in sports,, which I was really
happy about because, ever since the nature retreat,, I considered Amos to be
like one of my best friends in school..
But I was really,, really thrilled when Mr.. Tushman called out Summer’s name for
the gold medal in creative writing..
I saw Summer put her hand over her mouth when her name was called,, and when she
walked up onto the stage,, I yelled, "Woohoo, Summer!”!"
as loudly as I could,, though I don’t think she heard me..
After the last name was called,, all the kids who just won awards stood next to
each other on stage, and Mr.. Tushman said to the audience:,
"“Ladies and gentlemen,, I am very honored to present to you this year’s Beecher
Prep School scholastic achievers..
Congratulations to all of you!”."
I applauded as the kids on stage bowed..
I was so happy for Summer..
"“The final award this morning,”," said Mr..
Tushman, after the kids on stage had returned to their seats,,
"“is the Henry Ward Beecher medal to honor students who have been notable or
exemplary in certain areas throughout the school year..
Typically,, this medal has been our way of acknowledging volunteerism or service
to the school.”.
I immediately figured Charlotte would get this medal because she organized the
coat drive this year,.
so, I kind of zoned out a bit again..
I looked at my watch:, 10:::56.. I was getting hungry for lunch already..
Henry Ward Beecher was,, of course,, the 19th century abolitionist— —and fiery
sermonizer for human rights—, —after whom this school was named,”, Mr.. Tushman was
saying when I started paying attention again..
“While reading up on his life in preparation for this award,, I came up on
a passage that he wrote that seemed particularly consistent with the themes
I touched on earlier,.
themes I’ve been ruminating upon all year long..
Not just the nature of kindness,, but the nature of one’s kindness., The power of
one’s friendship., The test of one’s character., The strength of one’s courage—”.
And here the weirdest thing happened:.
Mr.. Tushman’s voice cracked a bit,, like he got all choked up.. He actually
cleared his throat and took a big sip of water..
I started paying attention, for real now, to what he was saying..
"“The strength of one’s courage,”." he repeated quietly,, nodding and smiling..
He held up his right hand like he was counting off..
"“Courage., Kindness., Friendship., Character..
These are the qualities that define us as human beings, and propel us,, on
occasion,, to greatness..
And this is what the Henry Ward Beecher medal is all about:, recognizing greatness..
“But how do we do that?? How do we measure something like greatness?? Again,, there’s
no yardstick for that kind of thing.. How do we even define it?? Well,, Beecher
actually had an answer for that.”.
He put his reading glasses on again,, leafed through a book,, and started to
read.. "“‘Greatness,’," wrote Beecher,, "‘lies not in being strong,, but in the right
use of strength.. He is the greatest whose strength carries up the most hearts."
And again,, out of the blue,, he got all choked up.. He put his two index fingers
over his mouth for a second before continuing..
"“‘He is the greatest,’”," he finally continued,, "“‘whose strength carries up
the most hearts by the attraction of his own.’."
Without further ado,, this year I am very proud to award the Henry Ward Beecher medal
to the student whose quiet strength has carried up the most hearts..
“So, will August Pullman please come up here to receive this award?
Floating.
PEOPLE STARTED APPLAUDING before Mr..
Tushman’s words actually registered in my brain..
I heard Maya,, who was next to me,, give a little happy scream when she heard my name,.
and Miles,, who was on the other side of me,, patted my back..
"“Stand up,! get up!”!" said kids all around me,. and I felt lots of hands pushing me
upward out of my seat,, guiding me to the edge of the row,, patting my back,, high-fiving me..
"“Way to go,, Auggie!”! “Nice going,, Auggie!”!"
I even started hearing my name being chanted. "Auggie! Auggie! Auggie!"
I looked back and saw Jack leading the chant,, fist in the air,, smiling, and
signaling for me to keep going,. and Amos shouted through his hands, "Woohoo, little dude!"
And I saw Summer smiling as I walked past her row,. and when she saw me look
at her,, she gave me a secret little thumbs-up and mouthed the silent "“cool beans”" to me..
I laughed and shook my head like I couldn’t believe it..
I really couldn’t believe it..
I think I was smiling..
Maybe I was beaming,. I don’t know..
As I walked up the aisle toward the stage,, all I saw was a blur of happy
bright faces looking at me,, and hands clapping for me.. And I heard people
yelling things out at me:. "“You deserve it,, Auggie!”! “Good for you,, Auggie!”!"
I saw all my teachers in the aisle seats,, Mr.. Browne and Ms.. Petosa and Mr..
Roche and Mrs. Anatabi and Nurse Molly and all the others:. and they were
cheering for me, woohooing and whistling..
I felt like I was floating.. It was so weird.. Like the sun was shining full
force on my face and the wind was blowing..
As I got closer to the stage,, I saw Miss
Reuben waving at me in the front row, and then next to her was Mrs.. G, who was
crying hysterically—.
—a happy crying—. —smiling and clapping the whole time..
And as I walked up the steps to the stage,, the most amazing thing happened:.
everyone started standing up.. Not just the front rows,, but the whole audience
suddenly got up on their feet,. whooping,, hollering,, clapping like crazy.. It was a
standing ovation..
For me..
I walked across the stage to Mr.. Tushman, who shook my hand with both his hands
and whispered in my ear:, "“Well done,, Auggie.”."
Then he placed the gold medal over my head,, just like they do in the Olympics,,
and had me turn to face the audience.. It felt like I was watching myself in a
movie, almost,. like I was someone else..
It was like that last scene in Star Wars Episode 4: A New Hope, when Luke
Skywalker,, Han Solo,, and Chewbacca are being applauded for destroying the Death Star..
I could almost hear the Star Wars theme music playing in my head as I sit on the
stage..
I wasn’t even sure why I was getting this medal,, really..
No,, that’s not true..
I knew why..
It’s like people you see sometimes, and you can’t imagine what it would be like
to be that person,. whether it’s somebody in a wheelchair or somebody who can’t
talk.. Only, I know that I’m that person to other people,.
maybe to every single person in that whole auditorium..
To me,, though,, I’m just me.. An ordinary kid..
But hey,, if they want to give me a medal
for being me,, that’s okay.. I’ll take it..
I didn’t destroy a Death Star or anything like that,, but I did just get
through the fifth grade., And that’s not easy,, even if you’re not me.
Pictures.
AFTERWARD, THERE WAS a reception for the fifth and sixth graders under a huge
white tent in the back of the school..
All the kids found their parents,, and I didn’t mind at all when Mom and Dad
hugged me like crazy,, or when Via wrapped her arms around me and swung me
left and right about 20 times..
Then Papa and Tata hugged me,, and Aunt Kate and Uncle Po,, and Uncle Ben—.
—everyone kind of teary-eyed and wet-cheeked., But Miranda was the
funniest:. she was crying more than anyone, and squeezed me so tight that
Via had to practically pry her off of me,, which made them both laugh..
Everyone started taking pictures of me and pulling out their Flips,, and then
Dad got me,, Summer,, and Jack together for a group shot.. We put our arms around
each other’s shoulders,, and for the first time I can remember,, I wasn’t even
thinking about my face.. I was just smiling a big, fat, happy smile for all
the different cameras clicking away at me..
Flash,, flash,, click,, click. smiling away as Jack’s parents and Summer’s mom
started clicking.. Then Reed and Maya came over.. Flash,, flash,, click,, click.
And then Charlotte came over and asked if she could take a picture with us,, and
we were like,, "“Sure,, of course!”." And then Charlotte’s parents were snapping
away at our little group along with everyone else’s parents..
And the next thing I knew,, the two Maxes had come over,, and Henry and Miles, and
Savannah. Then Amos came over,, and Zamina. And we were all in this big,
tight huddle as parents clicked away like we were on a red carpet somewhere..
Luca., Isaiah., Nino., Pablo., Tristan., Ellie..
I lost track of who else came over..
Everybody,, practically.. All I knew for sure is that we were all laughing and
squeezing in tight against each other,, and no one seemed to care if it was my
face that was next to theirs or not.. In fact,, and I don’t mean to brag here,,
but it kind of felt like everyone wanted to get close to me.
The walk home.
WE WALKED TO our house for cake and ice cream after the reception.. Jack and his
parents and his little brother, Jamie., Summer and her mother., Uncle Po and Aunt
Kate., Uncle Ben,, Tata and Papa, Justin and Via and Miranda., Mom and Dad..
It was one of those great June days when the sky is completely blue and the sun
is shining, but it isn’t so hot that you wish you were on the beach instead.. It
was just the perfect day..
Everyone was happy.. I still felt like I was floating,, the Star Wars hero music in my head..
I walked with Summer and Jack, and we just couldn’t stop cracking up..
Everything made us laugh.. We were in that giggly kind of mood where all
someone has to do is look at you and you start laughing..
I heard Dad’s voice up ahead and looked up.. He was telling everyone a funny
story as they walked down Amherst Road Avenue.. The grownups were all laughing,,
too.. It was like Mom always said:, Dad could be a comedian.. I noticed Mom
wasn’t walking with the group of grownups, so I looked behind me.. She was
hanging back a bit,, smiling to herself like she was thinking of something sweet..
She seemed happy..
I took a few steps back and surprised her by hugging her as she walked.. She
put her arm around me and gave me a squeeze..
"“Thank you for making me go to school,”," I said quietly..
She hugged me close and leaned down and kissed the top of my head..
"“Thank you, Auggie,”," she answered softly..
"“For what?”?"
"“For everything you’ve given us,”," she said..
"“For coming into our lives..
For being you.”."
She bent down and whispered in my ear..
"“You really are a wonder,, Auggie..
You are a wonder."
Appendix. MR.. BROWNE’S PRECEPTS.
SEPTEMBER When given the choice between being right or being kind,, choose kind.. —Dr..
Wayne W.. Dyer OCTOBER Your deeds are your monuments..
—inscription on an Egyptian tomb NOVEMBER Have no friends not equal to yourself..
—Confucius DECEMBER Audentis fortuna iuvat.
(Fortune favors the bold.).
—Virgil JANUARY No man is an island, entire of itself..
—John Donne FEBRUARY It is better to know some of the questions than all of the answers.. —James
Thurber MARCH Kind words do not cost much., Yet they accomplish much.. —Blaise Pascal
APRIL What is beautiful is good,, and who is good will soon be beautiful..
—Sappho MAY Do all the good you can,, By all the
means you can,, In all the ways you can,, In all the places you can,, At all the
times you can,, To all the people you can,, As long as you ever can..
—John Wesley’s Rule JUNE Just follow the day and reach for the sun!.
—The Polyphonic Spree,, “Light and Day” POSTCARD PRECEPTS CHARLOTTE CODY’S PRECEPT
It’s not enough to be friendly.. You have to be a friend.
Reed KINGSLEY’S PRECEPT Save the oceans,, save the world!.
—Me!
TRISTAN Fittle Holden's PRECEPT If you really want something in this
life,, you have to work for it.. Now quiet,. they’re about to announce the lottery numbers!.
—Homer Simpson Savannah WITTENBERG’S PRECEPT Flowers are great,, but love is better.. —Justin
Bieber HENRY JOPLIN’S PRECEPT Don’t be friends with jerks.. —Henry Joplin.
MAYA MARKOWITZ’S PRECEPT, All you need is love.. —The Beatles.
AMOS CONTI’S PRECEPT, Don’t try too hard to be cool..
It always shows, and that’s uncool.. —Amos Conti.
XIMENA CHIN’S PRECEPT, To thine own self be true..
Hamlet, Shakespeare.
JULIAN Albans' PRECEPT, Sometimes it’s good to start over..
—Julian Albans.
SUMMER DAWSON’S PRECEPT, If you can get through middle school
without hurting anyone’s feelings,, that’s really cool beans.. —Summer Dawson.
JACK WILL’S PRECEPT, Keep calm and carry on!.
—some saying from World War II.
AUGUST PULLMAN’S PRECEPT, Everyone in the world should get a
standing ovation at least once in their life because we all overcome-eth the world..
—Auggie.
That's the end.
I hope you enjoyed the book. If you did, please subscribe and come back and catch
us in another story.